



Summary

A Certified UX Designer and Usability Analyst with more than 6 years of experience in executing the overall UX/UI design cycle, by combining creative, technical and usability viewpoints into engaging and optimised experiences. Multi-domain exposure across various Product Companies, Digital Agencies & Startups.



Experience

Sep 2018 -Sep 2021

Sr. UX Designer

Mindtree, Bengaluru, India

- Provided UX consulting and UI design services for a US based Healthcare equipments manufacturing and E-commerce company.
- Effectively evaluated the existing flow against established heuristics and identified potential usability issues.
- Reimagined the entire UX of their healthcare management website and mobile application and redesigned the User Interfaces.
- Developed a design system and ensured consistency across the web and mobile device platforms.
- Adapted to a cross-time zone team and smoothly managed design handoffs.

Feb 2017 -Aug 2018

UX Designer

VVDN Technologies, Noida, India

- Championed Product vision through prudent UX research, analysis, sketching, Lo-Fi wireframing and interactive prototyping.
- Designed high quality Web App to measure the traffic and usage of Wi-Fi services across various cities of India, employing latest UI/UX trends.
- Designed entire flow and created pixel perfect mocks of a mobile application for engineering implementation which aimed to configure Wi-Fi devices, measure frequency and strength of radio signals.
- · Articulated and rationalized decisions against insights, needs & business goals.

Jun 2015 -Jan 2017

Jr. UX Designer

To The New, Noida, India

- Led the overall UX process for complex website revamps and mobile applications, adopting UCA/UCD methods & best practices.
- Conducted Heuristic evaluation, User research, Information architecture design, Hi-Fi Prototyping, Stakeholder collaboration and User testing.
- Adopted an agile UX approach for a faster & effective design turnaround time.
- Presented design deliverables to regional/overseas cross functional team.

Jun 2013 -May 2015

UI Designer

Estelle, Hyderabad, India

- Redesigned search functionality to deliver a more usable and delightful experience.
- Defined Information architecture, functional flow, Use case diagrams and prepared UI specs for Web and Mobile.
- Collaborated in a multidisciplinary fast-paced environment and handled multiple projects whilst adhering to tight timelines.



Address

Thomond Village, University of Limerick, Castletroy, Ireland, V94 DP7N

Phone

+353 892391928

Email

rrai88540@gmail.com

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/rahul-rai-24707357/

Portfolio

www.behance.net/Rahul Rai



User Research

User Flows & Wireframes

Information Architecture Design

UI & Interaction Design

Interactive / Hi-Fi Prototyping

Usability Testing



Softwares

Sketch / Figma / Adobe XD

Invision / Axure / UXPin

Adobe Photoshop / Illustrator

Adobe After Effects

JIRA / Slack / Trello

MS Office / Keynote



Certificates

Design Thinking by IDF

HCI (Human Computer Interaction) by IDF

Usability Guide by IDF

Enterprise Design Thinking by IBM



Education

NIFT (Kangra, India)

Bachelor of Design (B.Des) | 2009-2013

University of Limerick (Ireland)

Masters of Arts

(Interaction & UX Design) | 2021-22



Client: Alpha Star
App: Dfly 360 App

Type: iPad & Smart watch App

Summary: The application enables automatic assignments of trips to pilots and flight attendants to make several arrangements before and after every flight. It will provide the Details about assignments, cab & hotel bookings, documents and other important information.

Responsibilities: Requirement gathering, Feature definition, User interviews, User flow, Information architecture, Card sorting, Wireframing, Visual design, Interactive prototyping

Client: GE Healthcare

Project: E-auctions website revamp **Type:** Responsive Web & Mobile

Summary: A full revamp of the existing website to make it more engaging. This website is a platform through which GE sellers post refurbished machines and equipments with two options which are direct buy or bidding. Buyers see the various listings posted by sellers and buy the items and further supply them to clinics or small health care centers.

Responsibilities: Audience profiling, Content audit and mapping, User interviews, Sitemap, Card sorting, Information architecture, Wireframing, UI design, Interactive prototyping, User testing

Client: Labour Market Regulatory Authority (Government body of Bahrain)

App: Wages Protection System App

Type: Web & Mobile App

Summary: The application enables the users to check and validate KYC documents of foreign workers, check their salary history, working tenure and make sure they get paid on time. It also allows the main users to manage several other app users and their specific roles in the organization.

Responsibilities: Requirement gathering, Contextual inquiry, User flow, Information architecture, Wireframing, UI design, Interactive prototyping, User testing

Client: Unilever

App: SWOP App (Scope of Work Online Planner)

Type: Web App

Summary: The application allows the users to create SOW, set-up the allowances and budget, add campaigns and non-comapigns, agree the quote with agency and complete the SOW approval. It also enables the users to track changes on a live version of SOW and once ready then finalise the SOW.

Responsibilities: Usability evaluation, Contextual inquiry, Screen flows, Information-architecture, Hi-Fi Wireframing, Visual design, Interactive prototyping, UI specifications

Client: Walmart

App: Area & Store Management App

Type: Web & Tablet App

Summary: The application allows the area and store managers to view and monitor the details of weekly CFF (Clean-Fast-Friendly) scores of all the stores in a particular area as well as a specific store. This app will help to determine which area/store is performing well and which one needs support / improvement plan.

Responsibilities: Requirement gathering, Contextual inquiry, User flows, Information architecture, Hi-Fi Wireframing, UI & Interaction design, Prototyping.